Hey, what's going on?
嘿，怎麼樣？
I found a note on my door.
我家門上有張紙條說 過來摩妮卡家
Come to Monica's quick.
Bring champagne and a 3 Musketeers bar?
帶香檳和三劍客糖果棒？
Yeah, I'll take that.
給我
What's up?
怎麼樣？
Monica and I are engaged.
-摩妮卡和我訂婚了 -我的天
Oh my god.
What's going on?
Congratulations.
恭喜你，她人呢？
Where is she?
I'm engaged!
我訂婚了！我訂婚了！
Yeah, she's been out there for 20 minutes.
她在那兒20分鐘了，你沒聽到嗎？
I'm surprised you didn't hear her on the way over.
I thought it was just a kid yelling, I'm gay, I'm gay.
我以為有個小孩在叫 「我是同性戀！」
Yeah, no, that guy moved.
Can I bring her in?
-可以帶她進來了嗎？ -讓她去吧，好感人
No, no, let her stay out there.
It's sweet.
I'm getting married!
我要結婚了！我要做新娘了！
I'm gonna be a bride!
Will not shut up!
不，我不閉嘴，因為我訂婚了！
Because I'm engaged!
Oh, big talk.
Why don't you come over here and say that to me, huh buddy?
只敢說！你敢上來這兒當面告訴我？
Yeah, my fiance will kick your ass.
我未婚夫會教訓你
Come on, apartment 20!
來呀，20號，20號
Apartment 20!
Okay, you get her in here, you bolt the door, I'll be in
你去弄她進來，你鎖住門 我躲在衣櫃裡
the closet.
When it hasn't been your day, Come on, we've been on here, But
I'll be there for you.
Okay, wait, wait, wait, okay.
等一下
What?
Okay, um, I just want to say that I love you guys so,
我要告訴你們我很愛你們…
so much And thank you for being here on my special night.
感謝大家都在這兒 在這個對我很特別的晚上
Our special night.
對我們特別的晚上
I mean, it just wouldn't be my night, our, our night, If you
我的這一晚不會… 我們的這一晚…
all weren't here to celebrate with me.
如果不是因為你們和我… 我們一起慶祝！
God damn it!
It's okay, I want this to be your night too.
沒關係 我願意這是你的特別的一晚
To Monica.
敬摩妮卡
No, come on, wait, stop it.
等一下，停
Okay, to Monica.
好，敬摩妮卡
To Monica.
So, have you decided on a band for the wedding?
你決定婚禮用的樂團了嗎？ 我也能做音樂演出的
Because, you know, I'm kind of musical.
Yeah, Pheebs, honey, she just got engaged a couple hours ago, I doubt
she's even had time to think about it.
Well, speaking of chiming in, Remember the time you burned down my apartment?
提到合奏 記得有人燒了我的房子嗎？
Yeah, you're on your own.
是，你自求多福
You know what we should do?
We should all get dressed up and go to have champagne at the
我們換衣服出門 去廣場飯店喝香檳
plaza.
Oh, okay, yeah.
But, uh, I can't stay too long, I gotta get up early for
a commercial audition tomorrow, And I gotta look good.
要早起去試鏡，精神必須要好
I'm supposed to be playing a 19-year-old.
我要演一個19歲的人
What?
什麼？
So when you said get up early, did you mean 1986?
你說要早起，是指1986年？
You guys don't think I look 19?
你們不覺得我像19歲？
Oh, 19!
We thought you said 90!
19！我們以為你說90
Okay, everybody, let's go!
好了，大夥兒，走吧
Let's go!
Hey, is the rest of my candy bar around here?
我剩下的糖還在嗎？
Oh, honey, no, you ate it all.
沒了，你吃完了
Oh, I was afraid of that.
我就知道
Oh.
You know what shoes would look great with this ring?
你知道什麼樣的鞋子 能配這只戒指？
Diamond shoes.
鑽石鞋子
You're not getting dressed.
你沒換衣服
Know what I mean?
知道我的意思吧？
Yeah, but I don't think we have time.
知道，不過沒時間了
There's gonna be a wedding.
要舉行婚禮了
You're gonna be the bride.
你要做新娘了
Two hundred people are gonna be looking at you in a clean, white
有200人會看到你穿著白紗
dress.
Let's do it.
來吧
So, are you the fairest one of all?
Hey, I could still play 19, right?
Yeah, but, Joey, you gotta dress younger.
I'm telling you, if you wear the right clothes, you can look any
age.
Really?
Yeah, you know, I work in fashion, and fashion is all about you.
Fashion is about me?
About youth!
Youth!
Listen up, Grandpa!
Chandler, it happens to lots of guys.
錢德，很多人都會這樣
You're probably tired.
You had a lot of champagne.
你累了，喝了太多香檳
Don't worry about it.
別擔心
I'm not worried.
我不擔心，我很驚訝
I'm, uh, I'm fascinated.
You know, it's, uh, it's like biology.
知道嗎？就像生物學一樣
Which is funny, because in high school, I, uh, I, I failed biology,
很好笑，高中時我的生物被當…
and tonight, biology failed me.
今晚生物學當掉我
Check it out.
聽看看，來賓進場時我要唱這首
Okay, I could play this while the guests are coming in.
Okay.
Twelve years old and addicted to pork.
No one thought Monica would marry.
She knew her way around a knife and a fork.
Okay, Phoebe, but, that's great, but...
Okay, so, so you're not convinced.
That's all right, because I got another one.
First time I met Chandler, I thought he was gay.
第一次見到錢德時 我以為他是同性戀
But here I am singing on his wedding day.
但我現在在他的婚禮上唱歌
Phoebe!
菲比，不要
If you would have let me finish, it goes on to say that
如果讓我唱完 後面說他大概不是同性戀
he's probably not gay.
Sure, you guys don't have this problem.
你們沒有這個問題 你們是木頭做的
You're made of wood.
Hey.
You look great.
你看來很不錯
Oh, thanks.
謝謝
You okay over there?
你還好嗎？
I don't know.
我也不知道？覺得有一點…
You know, I feel a little, um...
No, you know what?
Never mind.
你知道嗎？沒關係 我會沒事的
I'm gonna be fine.
Well, don't worry about it.
I mean, you were probably tired.
You'd had a lot of champagne.
It happens to everybody.
每個人都會的
Hey.
Hi.
Well, happy Monica tonight.
Well, thank you.
You too.
-摩妮卡之夜快樂 -謝謝，你也一樣
Thanks.
Hey, can you believe this?
Can you believe they are actually getting married?
他們真的要結婚了？
Well, sure, but I get married all the time, so...
是啊，我結了好幾次了
You okay?
-你還好嗎？ -我想是吧
Yeah, I guess.
I mean, do you think we're ever gonna have that?
你覺得我們會不會有那麼一天？
You mean, we, you and me?
你說「我們」，是指你和我？
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
We, you with someone, and me with someone.
「我們」是指你和別人 我和別人
Oh, you scared me a minute.
-還好，嚇了我一跳 -是啊，好可怕
I know, I know.
Shake it off.
I mean, no, it's just, it's just because you and I, we were,
因為我們倆在一起是噩夢
you know, we were like a nightmare.
No, but there were some good times.
-可是也有好時光 -當然，就像那次…
No, absolutely.
You know, like, there was, um...
Surely you can think of something good.
-你總想得起一點好的吧 -給我一分鐘
Just give me a minute.
Oh, well, yes, I can think of one good thing.
我想得出一件好事
What?
You, um, you were always really good at the, um...
你總是很…
At the, uh, stuff.
我很在行？
Yeah, I was good at the stuff.
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm, yep, yep.
I really liked your hands.
我真的很喜歡你的手
My hands?
我的手？
Yeah.
Yeah?
Mm-hmm.
Way to go, guys.
做得好，兄弟們.
You know, you, you were really good at this stuff, too.
你也有很多事很在行
Oh, I know.
我知道
What are you thinking about?
Just some stuff.
Hey, you know what we never did?
你知道我們從沒做過什麼嗎？
Oh, no, not that.
不是那個啦
Uh, we never, we never had a bonus night.
我們從沒有過「紅利」夜
A what?
-什麼？ -「紅利」夜
You know, a bonus night.
You know how two people break up, but then they get back together
兩個人分手了，然後見面度過最後一夜
just for one night?
One night, just, just sex.
No strings attached.
最後一夜，只是上床？ 沒有其他？
Yeah, yeah, we never had that.
對，我們從來沒有過
Oh.
Okay, this is getting a little crazy, so...
這有一點怪怪的
I mean, I'm, I'm sure it would be amazing, but I gotta say,
我相信一定會很棒的…
I really, really don't think it would be a good idea, you know?
但我想這不是個好主意
I really, really don't.
Well, at least I can still do some things.
Sup?
怎麼樣？
Sup, dude?
怎麼樣，老兄？
Take whatever you want, just please don't hurt me.
要什麼隨便拿，不要傷害我
So you play a little PlayStation, huh?
你玩電動遊戲吧，嗯？
That's whack.
有夠遜
PlayStation is whack.
電動遊戲很遜
Sup if the whack PlayStation sucks.
怎麼樣，遜電動遊戲 怎麼樣？
Huh?
Come on, am I 19 or what?
怎麼，像不像19歲？
Yes.
On a scale from one to ten, ten being the dumbest a person
對，從一到十評分 十分是一個人看來最笨的樣子…
can look, you are definitely 19.
你絕對是19
Come on, man, really?
真的，多大？
How old?
Young.
You're a man-child, okay?
很年輕，你是男人孩子，好嗎？
Now go get changed, because everybody's ready, and please, oh please, keep my
去換衣服，大家都準備好了 拜託，拜託，內褲別還我
underwear.
Oh, thanks.
謝謝
Okay.
Joe?
Yeah?
Uh...
You've had a lot of sex, right?
你和人上床很多次，對不對？
What, today?
何時，今天？
Some, not a lot.
有幾次，沒有很多
Well, it's just the reason that I'm asking is because I had kind
我問你是因為我有一點…
of, uh...
I was unable to...
我不能…
I mean, I really wanted to, but I couldn't...
我很想，可是不能…
I cannot believe I'm asking advice from somebody who's wearing that hat.
I had an incident.
我發生了一個意外
Don't worry about that, man.
不要擔心，有時會這樣的
That happens.
It's happened to you?
-你也碰過？ -對，有一次
Yeah.
Once.
Well, what'd you do?
-那你怎麼辦？ -照樣做啊
I did it anyway.
Oh!
Phoebe, come on, let's go!
菲比，我們走吧
Why aren't you dressed yet?
你為什麼還沒換衣服？
I'm sorry, but I just wrote the best dance song for your wedding.
我替你的婚禮寫出了最佳歌曲
Check this out.
聽聽看
You know what, Phoebe?
I'll tell you what.
If you get ready now, I'll let you play it at the wedding.
如果你現在換好衣服 你就可以演出了
Really?
-真的？！ -對
Yes!
Oh, that's so exciting!
太令人興奮了，謝謝你
Thank you!
Thanks, Mon!
Oh, but Mon, if you touch my guitar again, I'm gonna have to
可是如果你再動我的吉他 我會打你
pound on you a little bit.
Fair enough.
好吧，去準備出門 我去叫大家
Now go get ready.
Okay.
Get everybody else.
I'm finally gonna start celebrating my...
終於可以開始慶祝我的…
I'm sorry.
對不起，我一定是 開了通往過去的門
Apparently, I've opened the door to the past.
Okay, uh, Monica, Mon.
Okay, what you just saw...
好，摩妮卡 你剛剛看到的是…
Can I ask you just a little question?
可以問你一個小小問題嗎？ 為什麼要在今晚？
Huh?
Why tonight?
What?
See, I've been waiting my whole life to be engaged.
我花了一輩子等著訂婚…
And unlike some people, I only plan on doing this once.
不像某些人，我只計劃做一次
So, you know, maybe this is selfish, and I'm sorry about it, but
I was kind of hoping tonight could just be about that.
可能這很自私，我很抱歉 但我希望這是今晚的焦點
Oh, honey, but it is.
No, it's not.
No, no, now it's about you and Ross getting back together.
現在焦點是你們的復合
What?
See, yeah, um, you kind of stole my thunder.
你看，你們搶了我的鋒頭
Okay, ho, ho.
We did not steal your thunder because we are not getting back together.
我們沒有搶了你的鋒頭 我們沒有要復合
Yeah, no.
是啊，沒有要復合 而且沒有人看到
And you know what?
Nobody even saw.
Yeah.
That's true.
沒錯
Hey, I swear.
We just kissed.
-我們只是吻了一下 -只是一個吻
It was just a kiss.
You guys kissed?!
你們吻了？！
What does this mean?
那是什麼意思？！
Are you, are you getting back together?
Can I sing at your wedding?
你們復合了嗎？ 我可以在你們婚禮上演唱嗎？
Thunder being stolen.
鋒頭被搶了
Okay, come on.
It is nothing.
Monica, come on.
Let's not make a big deal out of this.
-菲比，沒有什麼 -不要小事化大
It was a one-time thing.
只有發生一次，根本不算什麼
It doesn't even matter.
Oh, my God.
我的天
I cannot believe you guys are talking about this.
你們竟然在談論這件事
The problem's in the bedroom between a man and a woman.
臥房裡的問題是兩人之間的事
All right?
好嗎？錢德已經盡力了
Now, Chandler is doing the best he can.
I don't think that's what they were talking about, Joe.
我想他們不是在討論這事
No, but let's talk about it.
我們還在談這件事
What a great night.
Chandler can't do it.
These guys kissed.
What?
You guys kissed?
This is huge.
No, it's not.
It's really not huge.
And people thinking it's huge has led Monica to believe that we are
大家覺得這事大條 讓摩妮卡覺得…
stealing her thunder, which we are not.
我們搶了她的鋒頭 我們沒有
Well, we're still talking about it, aren't we?
Well, yeah, that and Chandler's problem.
那件事，還有錢德的問題
Monica, Monica, Monica, listen, listen, listen, listen.
Would it make you feel better if we all stopped talking about Ross
如果我們不再談羅斯和瑞秋 你會不會覺得好一點？
and Rachel?
Yeah, that would be lovely.
-會很好 -沒問題
You got it.
Okay.
Now, I can pass for 19, right?
來，我看起來可以像19歲吧？
Yes, you can pass for 19.
對，你可以看起來像19歲
Really?
-真的？ -對
Yes.
Seriously?
-認真的？ -認真的？
Seriously, no.
認真的說，不，你可以扮演 你的年紀，也就是31歲
Okay?
You can play your own age, which is 31.
31.
I'm 30.
No, you are not.
喬伊，你不是，你31歲
You're 31.
Oh, crap.
真爛！
Okay, so the plaza, okay?
We'll get us some Mai Tais.
Maybe no more for you, though.
去廣場飯店，叫些邁泰？ 但你別再喝了
You know what?
I think that I don't feel like going to the plaza anymore.
我不想去了
Why, Monica?
This is ridiculous.
摩妮卡，這太好笑了
I don't want to talk about it.
我不想談這件事 尤其是和你
I don't, I don't.
Especially with you.
Psst.
That is whack.
有夠遜
Yes.
Okay, I think I'll play it at the wedding.
我會在婚禮唱這首歌
Yeah?
Well, we'll see if they actually let you play.
要看他們是不是真的讓你演唱
Huh?
I mean, they tell you anything you want to hear.
他們會說你想聽的話…
Like, like, you look 19.
像是，「你看起來像19歲」
And then they just take it away.
然後又反悔，說：「不，你不像」
Like, like...
No, you don't.
Um, I don't think Monica's going to take this away.
這件事摩妮卡不會反悔的
Wouldn't she?
她會嗎？
Well, it's starting to sound like wood cheese.
Man, I could go for some wood cheese right now.
Guess who?
猜猜是誰
Hey.
Hey, I just realized we kind of left some stuff up in the
我們似乎還有些事沒解決
air.
What do you think Monica meant when she said I don't want to
talk especially with me?
「我不想談」特別是和我 是什麼意思？
I mean, why not especially you and me?
為什麼不特別是你和我？ 是我們兩人在接吻耶
We were both out there kissing.
Still thinking about it, huh?
你還在想那件事？
No, Sarah, I'm serious.
Seriously, what did she mean by that?
我是認真的，她說：「尤其是你」 是什麼意思？
Especially you.
Who cares?
-誰在乎啊？ -我在乎
I care.
And so do I.
我也在乎
You know what?
I have to go talk to her.
Will you let me just get changed?
我要和她談談 讓我換衣服好嗎？
Okay, sure.
Am I going to let you watch me undress?
我要讓你看我換衣服嗎？
No.
不
I can't believe her.
我不相信她竟然如此 她就是這樣
You know, it's just, it's so typical.
Now, Monica, I know you're upset, but don't forget there is going to
我知道你不高興 可別忘了要舉行婚禮了
be a wedding.
You are going to throw the bouquet and then there's going to be
你會要丟捧花，然後去蜜月
a honeymoon maybe in Paris.
-可能去巴黎 -巴黎？
Paris?
We will take a moonlit walk on the rue de la bleh bleh
我們會在月光下的 那叫什麼來著的大道上散步
bleh.
Keep talking.
繼續說
Then we will sprinkle rose petals on the bed and make love.
會在床上灑玫瑰花瓣，做愛…
Not just because it's romantic, but because I can.
不是因為那很浪漫 而是因為我可以
I love you.
我愛你
Bonjour, monsieur.
Okay, don't say anything.
You might scare it away.
別說話，你會嚇跑它
It's Paris.
這是巴黎 誰知道我們在這裡？
Who knows we're here?
Hi, Pheebs.
我懂了
What's up?
Okay, you said I could sing at your wedding, so I'm just going
to need a small deposit.
What?
You know, just some good faith money to hold the date.
你知道，一筆錢來保留那個日期
Pheebs, we're not giving you a deposit for our wedding.
我們不會給你訂金
Oh.
I see.
They break your heart, don't they?
他們真能傷你的心
You know, I really need their permission.
我不需要他們的同意
Yeah, if you want to sing at their wedding, well, you sing at
你想在他們婚禮唱歌 就在他們婚禮唱歌
their wedding.
Yeah, and if you want to look 19, then you...
如果你想看起來像19歲 就…
You got to do something about your eyes.
你要修飾一下你的眼睛
What?
What's wrong with my eyes?
我的眼睛怎麼了？
We give you away.
There's just, there's too much wisdom in there.
他們出賣了你 裡頭有太多的智慧
Just put some tea bags on them for like 15 minutes.
在上面放茶袋敷15分鐘
Not to get rid of my wisdom?
Maybe just 10 minutes for you.
Give her the deposit.
給她訂金，給她戒指 我不在乎
Give her the ring.
I don't care.
Yes?
Monica, what did you mean before when you said you didn't want to
你是什麼意思，當你說…
talk to anyone, especially me?
你不想和任何人談 尤其是我？
What a great apology, and you accepted.
好棒的道歉，你接受了，再見
Okay, bye-bye.
No, no, seriously, seriously, what was the especially me part about?
不，我是認真的 「特別是和我」是怎麼回事？
Well, let's just say it's not the first time you've stolen my thunder.
這樣說吧 這不是你第一次搶我鋒頭的
What?
Hey, here's a thought.
我覺得…
Monica, what are you talking about?
摩妮卡，你在說什麼？
My sweet 16, remember you went to third base with my cousin Charlie?
我16歲的生日宴會上 你和我表哥上三壘
Ah, third base.
上三壘
It's all everybody at the party could talk about.
每個人都在講那件事
Monica, you know what?
The only reason I did that was because your party was so boring.
它會發生是因為你的宴會太無聊
We had a caricaturist!
我們請了一個策劃家
Whenever I get married, guess who won't be asked to sing somebody named
當我結婚時 猜猜不會請誰來演唱
Geller and somebody else ain't big!
叫蓋勒的還有叫賓的
Monica, your sweet 16 was like a million years ago, and yet, here
摩妮卡，你的16歲生日 是一百萬年前的事了
you are doing it again.
你現在又做了
Oh, Monica, I don't want to steal your stupid thunder.
我不想搶你的笨鋒頭
Oh, please, why else would you have made out with Ross?
還有什麼原因你會和羅斯親熱？
Got me.
我不知道
All right, easy, mimey.
The moment has passed.
別亂來，時機已逝，不會發生了
It ain't gonna happen.
I just thought it'd be nice if I could have just this one
如果今晚的注意力都在我身上就好了
night.
I swear, I never wanted any part of your night.
我沒有想要過搶你的鋒頭
No one was supposed to see us kissing.
不應該有人看到我們的
Oh, is that why you did it in the secret hallway where nobody
所以你們就在秘密走廊上做 因為沒有人會到那兒去？
ever goes?
Uh, Rachel, I've been thinking.
瑞秋，我想過了
I don't think us getting together tonight is such a good idea.
我覺得我們今晚 在一起的主意不是很好
I'm calling it off.
我退出
Way to save your dignity, my ma'am.
挽救尊嚴的好方法
Monica, why?
Why would I ever want to take away from your night?
摩妮卡，我為什麼要搶走 屬於你的晚上？
I don't know.
我不知道，也許你有一點生氣
Maybe you're feeling a little resentful.
Maybe, uh, maybe you thought that you'd get married first.
你以為你會先結婚的
Maybe you can't stand the fact that your formerly fat friend is getting
你那個以前很胖的朋友會先結婚
married before you.
Oh, wow.
That, you know what?
哦…你知道嗎？太不公平了
That is so unfair.
You know what?
Now I want to steal your thunder.
現在我想搶你鋒頭了
Come on, Ross, let's go have sex.
羅斯，走，我們上床去
I can't believe you're gonna have sex on my engagement night.
你竟然在我的訂婚夜做愛
Well, somebody should.
總得有人做
Look, uh, if we're gonna do this...
如果我們要做…
We are not gonna do this, all right?
She's just gonna think that we're doing it.
我們沒有要做 只是要讓她以為我們有
I see.
So everybody wins.
我懂了，人人都是贏家
Who is it?
-是誰？ -是摩妮卡，開門
Monica, open up.
Okay, well, Ross, stop it, please.
羅斯，停一下 拜託，等一下
Wait a minute.
Ow!
Yeah, you like that, baby?
寶貝，你喜歡嗎？
May we help you?
有什麼事嗎？
I just wanted to say that I hope you do have sex tonight,
and I hope that you guys get back together.
But I must warn you, the night that you announce your engagement, I'm
我警告你，你宣佈訂婚時…
going to announce that I'm pregnant.
我會宣佈我懷孕了
How is that ever going to happen?
那怎麼可能呢？
All right, Monica, do you want to know why I was with Ross
你想知道今晚 我為什麼會和羅斯在一起？
tonight?
I know why.
-我知道為什麼 -你不知道
No, you don't know why.
Okay, why?
Because.
-好，為什麼？ -因為我很傷心
Because I was sad.
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
Look, I am so, so happy for you guys.
很為你們高興
But you getting married just reminds me of the fact that I'm not.
但你要結婚這件事 提醒了我，我沒有
I'm not even close.
八字都沒一撇
And I don't know, maybe I just wanted to make myself feel better.
也許我只想讓自己好過一點
And I know that that's dumb, but, oh, my God, you were so
我知道這很笨 可是羅斯結婚時…
depressed when Ross got married that you slept with Chandler.
你沮喪得和錢德上床
I don't care.
我無所謂，和她上床的是我
She slept with me.
Anyway, sweetie, I'm so sorry I ruined your night.
甜心，很抱歉毀了屬於你的今晚
I'm sorry I almost made you sleep with Ross.
我很抱歉讓你幾乎和羅斯上床
Well, I'm going to take off.
我要走了
Congratulations, man.
-恭喜 -謝謝
Thanks.
And, uh, Rachel.
瑞秋…
Yeah.
What can I say?
我能說什麼呢？
You missed your chance.
你失去了你的機會
From now on, the only person who's going to enjoy these bad boys
從現在起，只有我能享受他們了
is me.
That's right.
沒錯，我整夜留在這裡 錢德永遠不會…
We thought Phoebe would leave, but she just stayed and stayed.
但她留了下來
That's right, I'm here all night, and Chandler will never get paid.
Here's a dollar Consider it a deposit.
Please sing at our wedding.
算是訂金，請在我婚禮上演唱
Oh, thank you.
哦，謝謝
Okay.
Oh, now.
Who will perform the ceremony?
現在誰會在婚禮表演
Oh, oh, oh.
I'll pound on him in the morning.
我早上再打他